Finding Aid for the Nat Segaloff Papers PASC.0354
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Hollywood Blacklist, Series 2.
  - Ephemera, Subseries 1.
    - Lees-Rinaldo Doc ("The Treasurer's Report") (Box 2)
      Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. To access digital materials you must notify the reference desk in advance of your visit.
    - Mogul Photographs (Box 2)
      Photos of Hollywood moguls obtained as press materials for the first "The Waldorf Conference" production by LA Theatreworks: Barney Balaban, Dore Schary, Samuel Goldwyn, Louis B. Mayer, Harry Cohn, Spyros Skouras, etc.
    - Palmer Raids and Closed-Door McCarthy (Box 3)
      Pamphlet about the Palmer Raids prepared by the Labor Research Association, and documents released online of closed-door sessions of Joseph McCarthy's committee. Also Life magazine feature on "McCarthy and the U.S. Army"
    - Presskit: Academy of Motion Picture Arts & Sciences Exhibit (Box 2)
      in apology for their bestowing an Oscar on Kazan, AMPAS in 2001 asked blacklist era scholar Larry Ceplair to curate an exhibit (opened in 2002) about the effects of the blacklist on freedom of expression. Nat contributed several items to this exhibit. This presskit includes documentation and other information.
    - Red Channels (Box 2)
      signed by Vincent Hartnett (the book's co-author) to Grace Jackson Broecker, who has gone through it to annotate various people named as "Negro" and "Jew."
    - Red Treason in Hollywood (Box 1)
      Myron Fagan is at it again, this time for the movies (fragile newsprint).
    - Red Treason on Broadway (Box 1)
      Myron Fagan's self-published compendium of people he said were Red (very fragile newsprint).
    - Report on Blacklisting: I: Movies (Cogley) (Box 2)
      Seminal book on the subject and contain much anonymous testimony about the effects of blacklisting.
    - Report on Blacklisting: II: Radio - Television (Cogley) (Box 2)
    - SAG Remembers the Blacklist, 1997 (Box 2)
      Web transcript of the landmark 1997 event at which all the Guilds (but not, notably, the Television Academy on behalf of the TV industry) did a mea culpa for their support of the blacklist.
    - Salute to John Howard Lawson (Box 2)
      ": souvenir dinner program on the occasion of Lawson's 61st birthday. Signed by Lawson.
      Includes two copies of the original.
    - Supreme Court Brief: Alexander Meiklejohn of Cultural Workers in Motion Pictures, 1949 October (Box 2)
      Brief of Alexander Meiklejohn, of Cultural Workers in motion Pictures and Other Arts, and of Members of the Professions, as Amici Curiae.
      Dalton Trumbo, petitioner.
    - The Birth of the Blacklist, 1997 Octrober 19 (Box 2)
      Patrick Goldstein's article on the 50th anniversary of the Blacklist.
    - Thieves' Paradise (Box 2)
      Myron Fagan's play about Hollywood.
    - Unfriendly 10 Plea Up in Court Today, 1947 December 12 (Box 2)
      Volume XCVI, no. 36 of The Hollywood Reporter
  - Audio Visual Materials, Subseries 2.
    Includes A/V Waldorf Conference materials.
    SUBSERIES INCLUDES DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. To access digital materials you must notify the reference desk in advance of your visit.
    - ACLU Video Hollywood Ten, 1999; VHS (Box 42)
      Screening copy of Nat's 1999 ACLU of Southern California Bill of Rights Dinner tribute.
    - Blacklisted: The Man Behind the Door, audio cassettes (Box 42)
      Tony Kahn's radio drama about growing up with the fear that J. Edgar Hoover was going to come for him because his father, Gordon Kahn, was blacklisted.
    - Blacklisting: Then and Now, 1994; VHS (Box 42)
      screener of an ACLU/Massachusetts event
    - Blacklisting: Then and Now, 1994 November 5; beta SP tape (Box 43)
      Video recording of the 11-5-94 dinner by the ACLU of Massachusetts at which Ring Lardner, Jr., John Randolph, and Michael Moriarty were honored. Produced by Segaloff.
    - Hollywood Fights Back, 1947 October 26-November 2 (Box 82)
      Scope and Contents
      Original broadcasts.
    - Hollywood Fights Back Again, 2007 October 26 (Box 82)
      2 CDs.
      ACW/SC recreation.
    - Hollywood on Trial (Box 42)
      Aircheck of TCM's broadcast of the uncut 105-minute documentary.
      Includes VHS and 1 DVD.
    - Hollywood on Trial, 1976; beta SP tape (Box 43)
      Copy of 1976 feature documentary transferred from laserdisc. This is the 90-minte version once prepared for PBS, not the uncut 105-minute version that TMC licensed years later
    - Hollywood Ten, 1999 December 15; beta SP tape (Box 42)
      20-minute fundraising film directed by John Berry with home movies and readings by the Hollywood Ten
    - Hollywood Ten, 1999 December 15; beta SP tape (Box 43)
      Produced by Nat Segaloff for the ACLU of Southern California's honoring of the Hollywood Ten at the Bill of Rights Dinner (1999).
    - Hollywood Ten tribute, 1999 (Box 42)
      1 DVD.
    - League of American Writers, 1942; VHS (Box 42)
      Screener of "The Treasurer's Report" Academy Film Archives' reconstruction of a 16mm silent home movie by blacklisted writers Robert Lees and Fred Rinaldo for the League of American Writers.
    - Memorial Celebration for Robert (Bobby) Lees (1912-2004) (Box 42)
      Robert Lees televised murder reports, WGA memorial service, and interviews afterward.
      Lees was an American television and film screenwriter, best known for writing several Abbott and Costello films. Lees was blacklisted and continued to work under the name J. E. Selby.
      4 DVDs.
    - Point of Order, 1954; VHS (Box 42)
      Screener of Emile d'Atonio's famed documentary of the 1954 Army-McCarthy hearings
    - Ring Lardner, Jr, 1999; beta SP tape (Box 43)
      From the ACLU/SC dinner. In it, Lardner announces that it will be his last public appearance.
    - Salt of the Earth, beta SP tape (Box 43)
    - The MGM Story, 1950; VHS (Box 42)
      Documentary of the studio surrounding their release of "Lust for Life" hosted by then-VP of production Dore Schary.
    - Waldorf Conference, 2003; 2 DAT (Box 42)
      Master tapes. 2003 production produced by Nat Segaloff and directed by John de Lancie as a benefit for the Writers Guild Foundation and the ACLU of Hollywood (a chapter of ACLU/SC). These are unedited and unmixed field master tapes.
    - Waldorf Conference, 1993 October 28; VHS (Box 42)
      Edited Chantal Westerman feature that ran 10-28-93 on "Good Morning America" everywhere in the US except Los Angeles where it was pre-empted by local TV news coverage of fires.
    - Waldorf Conference (Box 42)
      6 CDs, 1 DVD, and compact audio cassettes.
    - Waldorf Conference, 1993 October 25; VHS (Box 42)
      Rehearsal and interviews.
    - Waldorf Conference tapes 1-3, beta SP tapes (Box 43)
  - Waldorf Conference, Subseries 3.
    "The Waldorf Conference" is a play about the secret meeting held in New York's Waldorf-Astoria Hotel on November 24 and 25, 1947 among 48 film company businessmen to decide how the industry should react to the HUAC hearings just concluded in Washington from October 20-30 at which charges were leveled against 10 men for alleged Communist party membership. Among the agendas at the Waldorf meeting were several that had nothing to do with Communism: box office returns had fallen, TV was entering the scene. Wall Street was getting nervous about its investments in Hollywood, anti-Semitism was rearing its head against the mostly Jewish moguls, and, of course, they all hated each other. At the end of the second day the moguls called a news conference and announced the "Waldorf Peace Pact" by which no Reds would be employed by the studios, anybody who was accused of Communist sympathies would be discharged, and the ten men who were cited by the Congress for contempt would be immediately fired. Without giving it a second thought, the moguls had started the Blacklist.
    - Assorted Production/Research Materials (Box 79)
      rewrite -- book proposal -- notes for revisions -- outlines -- research notes.
    - Assorted Production/Research Materials (Box 80)
      Waldorf: ACLU/Writers Guild Foundation paperwork -- audio recordings of rehearsal (of 1993 original) -- ACLU/SC Bill of Rights Dinner souvenir journals from December 15, 1999.
    - Assorted Production/Research Materials (Box 81)
      Four-volume set of manuals on how the Waldorf-Astoria runs -- Waldorf cookbook.
    - Production/Research Materials (Box 78)
      Re-writing process binder -- KCRW production binder -- Blacklistees -- Suitors (to make a feature film) -- production information -- contracts -- proposals -- hotel information -- casting information -- photographs -- press copy and releases -- LA Theatre Works information -- scripts.
- Research Material, 1970-; Series 3.
  Access to audio interviews are restricted to use within the UCLA Library Special Collections reading room. The audio interviews date back to the early 1970s and tie in directly with Segaloff's published articles and radio shows. The recordings were not intended for public distribution, but were created in lieu of taking notes (though most wound up on WEEI-FM or WITS-AM).
  SERIES CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIAL: Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. To access digital materials you must notify the reference desk in advance of your visit.
  - 3 Fugutives Interviews, 1989 January 15; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Junket interviews with film actors Nick Nolte and Martin Short, director, Francis Veber and producer, Lauren Shuler-Donner.
    Tape no. 255
  - Adams, Marjory: Interview, 1979 October 16; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the Boston Globe film critic of 52 years.
    Tape 201
  - Arterberry, Trent: Interview, 1979 April 28; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the mime.
    Tape 175
  - Assorted Research Material, papers (Box 73)
    AIDS (early public information) -- Consent Decree -- Filmmakers Co-op and Canyon Cinema Cooperative.
    Folder titles. See Segaloff annotations for content information.
  - Assorted Research Material, papers (Box 74)
    Friedberg, A. Alan -- Glossary of Variety-ese -- How to Succeed in the Film Business Without Really Trying -- Lugosi v. Universal -- Production Code -- Sack Theatres, Boston (clippings).
  - Assorted Research Material, papers (Box 74)
    Friedberg, A. Alan -- Glossary of Variety-ese -- Lugosi v. Universal -- Production Code -- Sack Theatres, Boston.
  - Assorted Research Material (Box 75)
    Sack Theatres, Boston -- SAG History -- Silent Movie Theatre -- Three-D (3-D) -- Alien Voices (Trademark Info and Forms) -- Welles, Orson Cinema and Film School.
    Includes 2 CDs.
  - Assorted Research Material, papers (Box 76)
    Welles, Orson Cinema and Film School -- Directing Workshop -- Film Appreciation and Syntax -- Film Comedy -- Film History.
  - Bacall, Lauren: Interview, 1987 August 7; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Actress talks about the film, "Mr. North", John Huston and Humphry Bogart.
    Tape no. 242.
  - Bauer, Belinda: Interview, 1979 September 25; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the actress in "Winter Kills."
    Tape 189
  - Beaches Interview, 1988 November 8; 2 audio cassettes (Box 25)
    Interviews about the film with the writer of Beaches screenplay, Mary Agnes Donahue, Beaches director, Garry Marshall, and another film director, William Friedkin.
    Tape nos. 265, 266. Tape 3 of 3 missing.
  - Beaches Interview, audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interview with actors: Barbara Hershey; Marcia Leeds; Mayim Bialyk and Bette Midler about the film, "Beaches."
    Tape 251.
  - Benson, Robby: Interview, audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the actor/writer.
    Tape 164
  - Berman, Susan: Interview, 1981 October 21; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the author, and daughter of a famous Vegas mobster.
    Tape 165
  - Bird, Larry: Interview, audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the basketball player.
    Tape 161
  - Bridges, James: Interview, 1980 June 24; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the writer and director of "Baby Maker."
    Tape 195
  - Butler, William "Bill": Interview, 1988 July 7; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interview with cinematographer, Bill Butler, about William Friedkin.
    Tape 281
  - Caan, James: Interview, audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the actor in the film, "Thief."
    Tape 194
  - Cassisi, John: Interview, 1980; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the child actor.
    Tape 186
  - Cecil B. Demille: The World's Greatest Showman, 1967 April 29; 7 " open reel audio tape (Box 5)
    Recorded from NBC television.
  - Charren, Peggy: Interview, 1989 September 28; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Telephone interview with the founder of Action for Children's Television.
    Tape 246
  - Closed Door McCarthy Hearings Transcripts, 1953-1954; Data CD (Box 82)
  - Cohen, Don: Interview, 1980 March 4; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the WEEI FM announcer.
  - Comandini, Pete: Interview (Box 82)
    Comandini headed YCM Labs, an early company that restored film.
  - Conrad, Randall: Interview, 1981 October 22; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the independent film maker.
  - Crimes and Misdemeanors Interview, 1989 September 23; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interview with Martin Landau and Joanna Gleason about the film, "Crimes and Misdemeanors."
    Tape 248.
  - Cronin, Laurel: Interview, 1980; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the actress.
  - Crowley, Mart: Interview, 1988 June 23; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interview with the writer of "The Boys in the Band," and William Friedkin.
    Tape 281. See also Collection 318, Mart Crowley Papers.
  - Cussler, Clive: Interview, 1989 July 29; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the author of, "Raise the Titanic."
    Tape 167
  - Dafoe, Willem: Interview, 1988 February 10; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interview with the actor about the film, "To Live and Die in L.A." and William Friedkin.
    Interview conducted in New York City. Tape 276
  - Dall, Chris: Interview, 1981 October 22; audio cassette (Box 26)
  - Daly, Tyne: Interview, 1989 June 5; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interview with the actress about her role in "Gypsy."
    Telephone interview. Tape 268
  - Dead, Denny: Interview, audio cassette (Box 26)
    Comedy improv. attempt with David Majka.
  - Fabulous Baker Boys Interviews, 1989 September 24; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Includes interviews with: Michelle Pfeifer, Beau Bridges, and Paula Weinstein.
    Tape 245.
  - Fitzgerald, Michael: Interview, 1980 March; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the producer.
    Tape 187
  - Fletch Lives, 1989 March 4; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interviews about the film with actors, Chevy Chase and Julianne Phillips.
    Tape 258.
  - Fonda, Jane: Interview, 1979 September 27; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the actress, probably about politics, not film.
  - Friedberg, Alan: Interview, 1979 December 20; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the theater executive.
    Tape 174
  - Friedkin, William: Interview, audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interview with the director and actor, Charles Champlin.
    Tape 279
  - Friedkin, William: Interview, 1987 October 25-1988 February 25; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Two interviews with the director for Segaloff's book on Friedkin.
    Tape 273
  - Friedkin, William: Interview, 1988 November 9; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interview with the director.
    Tape 254.
  - Friedkin, William: Interview, 1988 November 8; mini cassettes (Box 82)
  - Gardner, Gerald: Interview, 1989 March 31; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interview with the writer about William Friedkin.
    Tape 269.
  - Gertz, Elmer: Interview, 1988 April 24; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interview with the lawyer and civil libertarian about William Friedkin.
    Tape 267.
  - Gilroy, Frank D.: Interview, 1979 May 16; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the writer.
    Tape 173
  - Giovanni, June: Interview, 1989 April 5; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interview with Giovanni of the British Film Institute.
    Tape 269
  - Glick, Larry: Interview, 1974 March 4; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interview with radio host of the show, "The Exorcist" Phenomena.
    Tape 275
  - Grade, Lew: Interview, 1980 July 28; audio cassette (Box 26)
  - Grimes, Tammy: Interview, 1987 August 5; audio cassette (Box 25)
    The actress talks about the film, "Mr. North."
    Tape nos.: 242, 244.
  - Gross, Ed: Interview, 1988 February 24; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interview with the Chairman of the Board of International Business Management, Inc., about William Friedkin.
    Tape 271.
  - Grosso, Sonny: Interview, 1989 April 26; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interview with the host of the television program, "Cop Talk: Behind the Shield Episodes."
    Tape 268
  - Hayden, Tom: Interview, 1979 September 27; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the activist.
  - Huston, Angelica: Interview, 1987 August 7; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Actress talks about her role in the film, "Mr. North."
  - Inherit the Wind, 7 " open reel audio tape (Box 5)
    Narrated and condensed by Segaloff while in high school (1965).
  - Jackson, Larry: Interview, audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the exhibitor/distributor.
    Tape 170
  - John Huston Newspaper Articles (Box 82)
  - John Milius Backstory Interviews, 1984 August 5-2001 March 13; audio cassettes (Box 83)
  - Johnson, Lyn-Holly: Interview, 1981 September 29; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the actress of "Ice Castles."
    Tape 188
  - Johnson, Mark: Interview, 1988 Feburary 24; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interview with the producer about William Friedkin.
    Tape 278
  - Johnston, Ollie: Interview (Box 82)
    1 CD
    Disney animator.
  - Katzenberg, Jeffrey: Interview, 1988 November 4; mini cassettes (Box 82)
  - Kayucheck, Tom: Interview, 2 audio cassettes (Box 26)
    Interview with the manager of the Boston Music Hall on the hall closing.
    Tape 1 of 2. tapes 171, 172
  - Kleiler, David: Interview, 1981 September 21; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the film executive.
  - Kleiser, Randall: Interview, 1979 March 20; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Tape 200
  - Koren, Leonard: Interview, audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the design philosopher.
  - Kuralt, Charles: Interview, audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the journalist.
    Tape 166
  - Lamour, Dorothy: Interview, 1992 May 21 (Box 82)
  - Landis, John: Interview, 1980 June 30; 2 audio cassettes (Box 26)
    Interview (press luncheon) with the director of the film, "The Blues Brothers."
    Tape nos. 193, 194
  - Laughing Till it Hurts, 7 " open reel audio tape (Box 5)
    Dub of Peter Hazard original music for Nat Segaloff's 1969 compilation documentary on Charles Chaplin.
  - Leaf, Carolyn: Interview, 1979 September 30; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the filmmaker and animator.
  - Lee, Stan: Interviews (box 2 of 3), 1995-1996; 3 beta SP tapes, 1Hi8 video cassette (Box 27)
    Interviews conducted for the 1996 production of "Stan Lee: The ComiX-MAN" that Nat wrote, produced, and directed for Weller/Grossman Productions under contract to A & E Networks. These are the uncut field tapes of interviews with Lee, his wife and daughter, and many of the artists and celebrities who know him. They are of particular value to the history of comic books in America circa 1960-1980. Interviewees include: Lou Ferrigno; John Ritter; Gene Simmons; Harlan Ellison; Mark Evanier; Marvel Entertainment; John Buscena; Chris Barnes; Ed Asner; Stan Lee; John Semper; John Singleton; James Cameron.
    Segaloff acquired these tapes as a gift from the production company. Box inventory in box 1 of 3.
  - Lee, Stan: Interviews (box 1 of 3), 1996; 36 beta SP tapes (Box 30)
    BetaSP tapes of interviews conducted for the 1996 production of "Stan Lee: The ComiX-MAN" that Nat wrote, produced, and directed for Weller/Grossman Productions under contract to A & E Networks. These are the uncut field tapes of interviews with Lee, his wife and daughter, and many of the artists and celebrities who know him. They are of particular value to the history of comic books in America circa 1960-1980. Interviewees include: Lou Ferrigno; John Ritter; Gene Simmons; Harlan Ellison; Mark Evanier; Marvel Entertainment; John Buscena; Chris Barnes; Ed Asner; Stan Lee; John Semper; John Singleton; James Cameron.
  - Lee, Stan: Interviews (box 2 of 3), 1995-1996; 3 beta SP tapes, 1Hi8 video cassette (Box 41)
  - Legal Briefs Writers Meeting, 1978 November 11; 7 " open reel audio tape (Box 5)
    Participants: Arnie Reisman, Tony Kahn, Fred Barron, Jon Lipsky, Nat Segaloff, and David Ansen. "Legal Briefs" was a satiric sketch show to benefit the ACLU of Massachusetts.
  - Levin, Stan: Interview, 1979 September 17; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the writer/bureaucrat by Segaloff on WITS.
    Tape 190
  - Levine, Barry: Interview, audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the Harvard archivist.
  - Levine, Joseph E.: Interview, 1980 May 16; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the movie mogul for the film "Magic."
    Tape 177
  - Lewis, Shari: Interview, 1994; cassette tapes (Box 82)
    Pre-interviews for A & E "Biography."
  - License to Kill Interviews, 1989 July 6; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interviews (tape 1 of 2) about the film with: director, John Glen; singer, Wayne Newton; actress, Talisa Soto, and screenwriter, Michael G. Wilson.
    Interview conducted in New York City. Tape no. 256
  - License to Kill Interviews, 1989 July 6; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interviews (tape 2 of 2) about the film with: actors, Timothy Dalton and Robert Davi.
  - License to Kill Interviews, 1989 July 6; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interviews about the film with: director, John Glen; singer, Wayne Newton; actress, Talisa Soto, and screenwriter, Michael G. Wilson.
    Interview conducted in New York City. Tape no. 257
  - Lovelace, Linda: Interview, 1980 February 20; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the actress and author of "Deep Throat."
    Tape 172
  - Malone, Michael: Interview, 1980 April 3; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the charity director of "Little Brothers."
    Tape 163
  - Maltin, Leonard: Interview, 1993 April 14 (Box 82)
  - Mann, Michael: Interview, audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the writer and director of the film, "Thief."
  - Margolin, Janet: Interview, 1979 April 24; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the actress about the film, "Last Embrace."
  - Mcdonald, Gregory: Interview, 1985 May 15; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interview with the author of "Fletch" and other novels.
    Tape 260
  - McKellan, Ian: Interview, 1981 September 28; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the actor about D. H. Lawrence.
  - Milius, John: Interview, 1979 September 17; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the writer/director.
  - Milius, John: Interviews, 1980 August 8-2001 March 13 (Box 83)
    Interviews with the writer/director.
    22 CDs.
  - Mississippi Burning Interview, 1988 December 4; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interview with actors, Willem Dafoe, Gene Hackman, Frances McDormand and Alan Parker, director of the film, "Mississippi Burning."
    Tapes 249, 250
  - Morris, Garrett: Interview, 1979 March 30; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the actor/singer.
  - Mouris, Frank & Caroline: Interview, 1981; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the animator/filmmakers.
  - Newman, Shelly: Interview, audio cassette (Box 26)
  - Nimoy, Leonard: Interview, 1988 May 8; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interview with the actor and director of the film, "The Good Mother."
    Tape 260.
  - O'Brien, Ted: Interview, 1981 October 1; audio cassette (Box 26)